Bala Ganapathy Parthiban



Full-Stack Software Engineer

balaganapathy.parthiban@gmail.com

(+91)866723744



🕝 balaganapathy.dev 🎧 github/balaganapathyparthiban

Objective

A self-motivated software engineer with 4+ years of experience and considerable technical skill who possesses self-discipline and ability to work with minimum of supervision. Able to play a key role in web app development to ensure maximum accessibility, user experience and usability. A quick learner who can absorb new ideas and can communicate clearly and effectively.

Education

Sree Sastha Institute of Engineering & Technology 2013 - 2017 // Chennai, Tamilnadu, India Bachelor of Engineering in Electronic and Communication.

Relevant Experience

Senior System Engineer @ Infosys Pvt Ltd Jun 2020 - Present // Chennai, Tamilnadu, India

- Worked as part of an agile team to write modern, performant, and robust code to develop interactive web applications for a client BASF Pvt Ltd.
- ► Written an AWS lambda functions to calculate the weather data and to plot complex Graphs and Charts in Front end application.
- ► Works with various technologies such as React, Angular, Spring boot, PostgreSQL, AWS, Azure etc.
- ► Tested sites in various browsers and devices to ensure cross-browser compatibility and mobile responsiveness.
- ► Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, producers, clients, and stakeholders on a daily basis.

Software Developer @ Casperon technologies Pvt Ltd Oct 2018 - May 2020 // Chennai, Tamilnadu, India

- Worked with a team to build an on-demand and e-commerce web application for a diverse array of clients and internal projects.
- Work with various languages and frameworks such as React, Angular, css/scss, Nodejs, Python, MongoDB, Elastic search etc.
- ► Interacting with clients on a weekly basis and providing project oriented technological expertise and knowledge.

Open Source Projects

Easy Scrum // easyscrum.balaganapathy.dev

Web app built with React & Gun.js Decentralised database for Agile teams to estimate, prioritise product backlog & conduct retrospectives.

Quickshare // quickshare.balaganapathy.dev

File sharing in Quickshare is guick and easy by just sharing a link, you can send anything from photos, videos and zipped folders also can set and password for files, Web app was built with React, Go and Fiber.

Cloudbox // cloudbox.balaganapathy.dev

Cloudbox is an open source decentralised application able to securely store files, images, videos, audios and notes. Build with React, Web3.storage and Gun.js.

Skills

Programming Languages

- Javascript(ES6)
- Typescript
- ► HTML & CSS/SCSS
- ► Python
- ► Go
- ▶ Rust
- ▶ Java

Libraries & Frameworks

- ► Reactis
- ► Angular 2+
- Node.js, Express.js
- ► Flask
- Go Fiber
- GraphOL
- ▶ Web Socket & WebRTC

Database

- MongoDB
- ► PostgreSQL
- ► Neo4i
- ▶ Redis
- Elastic search

Tools & Platforms

- ► Git
- ► AWS
- Azure
- Firebase
- Docker & Docker Swarm
- Kubernetes

Learning & Certification

- Microservices with Node JS and React (udemy)
- Building Modern Web Application with Go
- Master Python programming by solving scientific projects (udemy)
- Docket Mastery with Kubernetes + Swam from Docker Captain (udemy)
- Machine Learning A-Z Hands on Python & R in Data Science (udemy)